rolls-roycemotorcars.com 2015-06-08

# Rolls-Royce Motor Cars Legal

This is the only official Rolls-Royce Motor Cars Limited website.

Rolls-Royce Motor Cars Limited is responsible for the content of this website. Rolls-Royce Motor Cars Limited is a company registered in England and Wales under company number 03522604 and has its registered office at Summit ONE, Summit Avenue Farnborough, Hampshire GU14 0FB.  
E-mail address : [enquiries@rolls-roycemotorcars.com](mailto:enquiries@rolls-roycemotorcars.com)

The terms below govern your use of this website and by accessing this website you agree to be bound by them. If you do not accept these terms, please do not use the website. We may change these terms at any time without notice by updating the terms shown on this website. It is your responsibility to review the website terms each time you enter the website to ensure you are aware of our latest terms and conditions. Your use of this website after a change has been made signifies your acceptance of the revised terms.

This website is for your personal use only and is not to be used for any commercial purpose.

The provision of details of products and services on this website are not, and should not be construed as, an offer to sell or supply such products or services, and the seller or supplier may always accept or reject your offer at its sole discretion.

All products and services on this website are subject to availability and may be withdrawn without notice. All products and services and all prices are also subject to change without notice.

These website terms should be read in conjunction with the separate terms and conditions for the sale or supply of the individual products or services which are referred to on this website. In the event of any inconsistency between these terms and the specific product or service terms and conditions, the latter shall prevail.

Whilst we have made every effort to ensure the information on this website is up to date and accurate, neither we nor any authorised Rolls-Royce Motor Cars dealership nor other third party can accept responsibility for your reliance on any information on this website.

Always check with your authorised Rolls-Royce Motor Cars dealership model availability and for precise information on vehicle model features, specifications and equipment, and in the case of approved used Rolls-Royce motor cars, current mileage details before ordering a vehicle.

Always check the terms on which any product or service is supplied before making any commitment.

You should seek your own independent financial advice in relation to any taxation or accounting matters referred to on this website.

The vehicle specifications on this website are, unless stated otherwise, for the UK market only.

These specifications (including what is optional and what is standard equipment) may vary in other markets. However some vehicle images may be of models supplied in other markets, for example showing left-hand drive, and not reflecting specifications in the UK.

The information and other materials contained in this website may not satisfy the laws in countries outside the UK. If you choose to access this website from outside the UK you are responsible for ascertaining to what extent local laws are applicable and compliance with local laws.

We cannot promise that this website will be uninterrupted, or free of errors, bugs or viruses and we will not be liable if, for any reason, this website is unavailable at any time or for any computer virus or system free. Access may be suspended at any time without prior notice being given.

The copyright in the material contained in this website belongs to Rolls-Royce Motor Cars or its licensors. No person may copy, modify, transmit, distribute, display, reproduce, publish, license or create works from any part of this material or otherwise use it for any public or commercial use without the prior express written permission of Rolls-Royce Motor Cars. You may only view or print individual pages for your own personal use.

The names, logos and images on this website which identify Rolls-Royce Motor Cars, or third parties and their products and services are proprietary marks of Rolls-Royce Motor Cars and/or the relevant third parties. Nothing contained in this website shall be deemed to confer on any person any licence or right on the part of Rolls-Royce Motor Cars or any third party with respect to any such name, logo or image.

The products, services and technology or processes described in this website may be subject to other intellectual property rights reserved by Rolls-Royce Motor Cars or its licensors or any relevant third parties. No licence is granted in respect of such intellectual property rights.

This site may contain (hypertext) links to other sites that enable users to leave this site and go directly to the linked site. The links are provided to assist users of this website and the inclusion of a link does not imply that we endorse or have approved the linked site. We do not control linked sites, and are not responsible or liable for their content or any link within such sites, or for any transmission received from any linked sites.

We recognise that bribery and corruption remain major issues in world trade, despite efforts to prevent them. We strive to ensure that our businesses are run with complete integrity and we have clear anti-bribery and corruption policies, which are fully supported by our directors to ensure that our employees remain untainted by bribery or corruption.

This website and the information, images, materials and other content shown are provided without any representation or endorsement being made and without any warranty of any kind, whether express or implied, including but not limited to, any implied warranties of satisfactory quality, fitness for a particular purpose, non-infringement, compatibility, security and accuracy. To the extent permitted by law, all such terms and warranties are hereby excluded.

Without limitation to the foregoing, although we take care to ensure that the information, images, materials and other content provided on this website are accurate, we give no warranties of any kind, express or implied, that they are accurate, complete or up to date. You should not rely on the information to make any decision or take any action. Neither we nor any authorised Rolls-Royce Motor Cars dealerships shall accept any liability for the accuracy or completeness of the information contained in this website or for any reliance placed by any person on the information.

In no circumstances shall Rolls-Royce Motor Cars or any authorised Rolls-Royce Motor Cars dealership be liable for any losses sustained and arising out of or in connection with use of this website or any site accessed from this website including, but not limited to, loss of profits, loss of data or loss of goodwill (whether direct or indirect) nor any economic, consequential, indirect or special loss.

If any of these terms are found to be illegal, invalid or otherwise unenforceable, then to the extent of such illegality, invalidity or unenforceability, such terms shall be deleted and severed from the website terms. The remaining enforceable terms shall continue in full force and effect and continue to be binding.

Nothing in these terms shall exclude or limit our liability for death or personal injury resulting from our negligence or shall affect your statutory rights if you are a consumer.

These terms shall be governed by and construed in accordance English law. Disputes arising in relation to them shall, unless expressly agreed otherwise, be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the English courts.

Telephone calls and e-mail correspondence with Rolls-Royce Motor Cars at the email addresses accessible through, or obtained from, this website may be recorded or monitored. By using these communication methods you are consenting to the recording or monitoring of your calls and e-mails.

* * *

Rolls-Royce Motor Cars Limited is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. We will only collect and use your personal information to deliver the Services and in accordance with the current data protection law in the UK. For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1988, the data controller is Rolls-Royce Motor Cars Limited of The Drive, Westhampnett, West Sussex, PO18 0SH.

Information collected and processed in the delivery of the Services includes but it not limited to your vehicle's: identification number (VIN), description, location, direction of travel, service data or incidents involving your vehicle, information about anyone making a Services call from your vehicle or under your account, the date, time and duration of your calls, (all calls may be recorded). Your Rolls-Royce vehicle may also be equipped with one or more sensing or diagnostic modules capable of automatically retrieving, recording, transmitting, or storing certain vehicle data, such as battery voltage, coolant temperature, mileage, air temperature, oil levels and other data relating to servicing requirements.

We may record or monitor your vehicle's location or other information when a) you or other occupants in your vehicle request the Services, b) your airbag deploys or a severe impact occurs, c) your vehicle is equipped to provide vehicle location services and you report your vehicle as stolen or d) as required by law.

We will use the information we collect from you to deliver the Services to you, manage your Services account, improve occupant and vehicle safety, for analysis and research purposes, improve your service experience at approved Rolls-Royce dealers and enhance your overall ownership experience.

We will share the information we collect with our service providers such as: roadside assistance and information service providers, emergency service dispatchers and providers, approved Rolls-Royce dealers, mobile communication service providers and any other entity that assists in delivering the Services solely for the purpose of providing the Services to you; we may also share information as necessary with third parties for analysis and research purposes in order to enhance the quality of the Services. All service providers or third parties are contractually obligated to keep your information confidential and use the information only as we specify. We may also disclose information to individuals designated by you to be contacted in an emergency. When required, we may release information, including location data, to comply with the law, in legal proceedings, to respond to subpoenas or court orders, in cooperation with law enforcement agencies, and to enforce the terms of our Agreement.

The Services employ wireless telephone networks that use radio channels to transmit voice and data. All data transmitted during the provision of the Services is automatically encrypted (using SSL), as is the industry standard for the transfer of confidential data via the internet. However, neither the privacy nor security of conversations or data over the wireless telephone networks can be guaranteed. Data may be transferred to countries outside of European Economic Area in order to ensure the effective delivery of the Services.

We may amend this privacy notice at any time. Comments or inquiries about our Privacy Policy should be directed to Rolls-Royce Customer Relations at +44 (0) 1243 384300.

* * *

## Privacy policy

Rolls-Royce Motor Cars Limited are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. We will only use your personal information in accordance with the current data protection law in the UK and this privacy policy.

This policy (together with our terms of use and any other documents referred to in it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us will be processed by us.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1988, the data controller is Rolls-Royce Motor Cars Limited of The Drive, Westhampnett, West Sussex, PO18 0SH.

We may update this privacy policy from time to time by publishing the amended version on our websites.

This privacy policy applies to personal information we hold about individuals. It does not apply to information we hold about companies and other organisations.

How do we receive your information?

We may receive information about you:

  * when you contact us directly, normally via our website or our customer services teams, whether to apply for one of our products or services or to make an enquiry or other request,
  * from our network of authorised Rolls-Royce Motor Cars dealerships,
  * from our other group companies and carefully selected business partners who provide products and services under one of our brands, and
  * occasionally from other third parties who may lawfully pass to us information about you.

Using your information

  * We may use your information (which we receive from you or third parties or learn from the way you use our products or services) for a variety of purposes, including:
  * to provide or manage any information, products and services you have asked for,
  * for marketing purposes, including market research,
  * to help us identify you when you contact us,
  * for general administration purposes,
  * to help us improve the quality of our products and services,
  * to help us detect and prevent fraud and money laundering,
  * to help us recover debts,
  * to carry out analysis and customer profiling, and
  * to identify other products and services which might be of interest to you and to inform you about our products and services (please see below).

We may share your information for any of these purposes with:

  * our other group companies in the UK and abroad,
  * authorised Rolls-Royce Motor Cars dealerships,
  * our carefully chosen business partners who provide products or services under one of our brands, and
  * our service providers and agents who perform services on our behalf, such as credit card processors and data management firms.

We may also pass your information to third parties:

  * if we have been asked to provide information for legal or regulatory purposes,
  * in relation to existing or future legal proceedings,
  * in the process of selling one or more of our businesses or to anyone to whom we may transfer our rights under any customer agreement we have with you,
  * for the purpose of preventing fraud/loss, for example to fraud prevention agencies.

The information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA, who work for us or one of our suppliers. By submitting your information, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with this policy.

Informing you about our products and services

We may use your information to contact you with news on our motor cars, other products and services (provided by us, our other group companies or our carefully selected business partners) which may be of interest to you and occasionally for market research purposes.

We may also pass your information to our other group companies, authorised Rolls-Royce Motor Cars dealerships and our other business partners for these purposes.

We, and these other parties, may contact you by post and telephone and, if you give us your prior agreement to do so, by email, SMS and other electronic means.

The range of products and services offered by us, authorised Rolls-Royce Motor Cars dealerships, our other group companies or selected business partners include:

  * Rolls-Royce motor cars,
  * motor related products and services, including (amongst other things) vehicle finance, leasing and ancillary insurances, vehicle accessories, vehicle emergency service, vehicle warranties and motor insurance.

You may opt out of receiving marketing communications from us on our vehicles and other products and services by ticking the appropriate box (if providing your information on this website) or at any time by telephone on +44 (0)1243 384000, or writing to us at Rolls-Royce Motor Cars Limited, CRM Department, The Drive, Westhampnett, Chichester. PO18 0SH, United Kingdom.

You may also contact us at the above address or telephone number if you have previously asked not to receive marketing communications but would now like to hear from us with news on our motor cars, other products and services.

Please note if you purchase a motor car from an authorised Rolls-Royce Motor Cars dealership or otherwise give your information to an authorised Rolls-Royce Motor Cars dealership, you will have a separate relationship with the dealership in relation to their use of your information and you will need to contact the dealership regarding any request you may have relating to their use of your information.

We will only send you marketing communications by email or other electronic means if you give us your agreement to do so. For example, we may inform you when inviting you to provide your email address that by providing your email address you will be indicating your agreement to receive marketing emails. If you give us your agreement and subsequently wish to opt out you may do so by clicking the unsubscribe link which we include on all our marketing emails or you may contact us at any time at the address or telephone number above.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure, although we will do our best to protect your personal information. However you recognise when providing your information to us through our website or when you send us or ask us to send you any of your confidential information by email, that the internet and email communications over the internet may not be secure. We cannot be responsible for any loss or unauthorised interception of information transmitted via the internet which is beyond our control.

Our website may contain links to other websites. Our privacy policy only applies to our website. We are not responsible for the content, privacy or security of other websites

A cookie is a small text file that some websites store on your computer.

Within this website cookies are used to improve the browsing experience for our customers. Rolls-Royce Motor Cars take your privacy seriously and the below information details the cookies used, how to prevent these being written and the impact of doing so on your browsing experience.

You can accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, you will not be able to use all the interactive features of the site if cookies are disabled.

Most recent web browsers allow control over the cookies saved through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "External link opens in new window").

Rolls-Royce Motor Cars are working to provide the ability for you to manage your cookie preferences within our website but this is currently under development. As an interim step below we have detailed all the cookies set by our websites, their purpose and details of how to opt out where available.

The cookies detailed on this website are based on the International Chamber of Commerce guide for cookie categories; Strictly necessary, Performance or Targeting.

Strictly necessary cookies let you move around the website and use essential features like secure areas, contact forms and so on. These cookies don't gather any information about you that could be used for marketing or remembering where you've been on the internet.

Performance cookies collect information about how you use our website e.g. which pages you visit, and if you experience any errors. These cookies don't collect any information that could identify you - all the information collected is anonymous and is only used to help us improve how our website works, understand what interests our users and measure how effective our advertising is.

Targeting cookies are linked to services provided by third parties, such as 'Like' buttons and 'Share' buttons. The third party provides these services in return for recognising that you have visited our website.

In addition, we also use 1st party, 3rd party and Persistance cookies, for more information on these please click here [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "External link opens in new window").

The tables below explain the cookies we use and why. The information is updated regularly but if a discrepancy is found then please contact us.

Cookie| Name| Purpose| More Information  
---|---|---|---  
Webtrends Analytics| 1st Party Cookies  
WT_FPC  
Responsive

3rd Party Cookies  
ACOOKIE

| The first party and third party cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use the site. The information is used to compile reports to improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. It processes IP addresses and also tracks for instance information about the usage of contact forms, video players, downloads, car configurators and "shares" to social media platforms. It also collects certain kinds of technical data, such as browser-types, as well as geographical data, such as the users' country, for example.

This statistical information allows Rolls-Roycemotorcars.com to improve the performance of their site.

To opt out of being tracked by Webtrends Analytics, go to

[WT-NAH]

WT_NAVI

| The WT_NAVI cookie is used by Webtrends Analytics in order to track what kind of navigation elements are being used on the site (main navigation, footer navigation or teasers).  
It also stores information about the source page and target page of the user who has clicked on the navigation element.  
AddThis social media sharing| _atuvc_| AddThis cookies allow users to share content via Social Networking websites and email. The __atuvc cookie is created and read by the AddThis social sharing site JavaScript on website in order to make sure the user sees the updated count if they share a page and return to it before the share count cache is updated. No data from this cookie is sent back to AddThis.|   
Google Analytics| _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmx  
_utmxx  
_utmz| These third party cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use the site. The information is used to compile reports to improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.| [Google privacy policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/ "External link")

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit  
  
Cookie| Name| Purpose| More Information  
---|---|---|---  
Merchantize| ngx_userid  
pid2  
sid{ic_client_id}  
ngx_{url_id}  
cvt  
dupCvt| Merchantize cookies are used by iCrossing for the purposes of user targeting and research and development. Additionally, at the user's option, we will collect HTTP cookies, which will be used for research and development and one-time tailoring. This data will only be used by iCrossing and our agents.

ICrossing's web server automatically collects some information about you when you request pages from iCrossing's server, including your IP address. This information does not identify you personally.

|   
  
Strictly necessary cookies

Cookie| Name| Purpose| More Information  
---|---|---|---  
VicinityUser| VicinityUser| This session cookie indicates that you are actively using the site. This cookie is deleted when you close your browser.|   
  
Performance cookies

Cookie| Name| Purpose| More Information  
---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics| _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmx  
_utmxx  
_utmz| These third party cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use the site. The information is used to compile reports to improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.| [Google privacy policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/ "External link opens in new window")

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit  
  
[Targeting](https://www.bt.com/static/includes/globalheader/cookies/more-about-cookies.html#target "External link opens in new window") cookies

Cookie| Name| Purpose| More Information  
---|---|---|---  
Merchantize| ngx_userid  
pid2  
sid{ic_client_id}  
ngx_{url_id}  
cvt  
dupCvt| Merchantize cookies are used by iCrossing for the purposes of user targeting and research and development. Additionally, at the user's option, we will collect HTTP cookies, which will be used for research and development and one-time tailoring. This data will only be used by iCrossing and our agents.

ICrossing's web server automatically collects some information about you when you request pages from iCrossing's server, including your IP address. This information does not identify you personally.

|   
  
Strictly Necessary Cookies

Cookie| Name| Purpose| More information  
---|---|---|---  
JSESSIONID| JSESSIONID| This session cookie indicates that you are actively using the site. This indicates, at any given time, how many users are visiting the site. This cookie is deleted when you close your browser.|   
  
Performance cookies

Cookie| Name| Purpose| More information  
---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics| _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmx  
_utmxx  
_utmz| These third party cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use the site. The information is used to compile reports to improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.| [Google privacy policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/ "External link")

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit  
  
If you give us information on behalf of someone else, you confirm to us that you have their permission to do so and that they are aware of the contents of this policy and do not have any objection to our processing their information in accordance with this policy.

You are responsible for informing us of any change in your details, such as a change of address. You have a right to ask us to correct any inaccuracies in the information we hold about you.

You have a right to ask what information we hold about you. We will charge you a small fee for this (the statutory fee is currently £10).

You may contact us at the address below for these purposes.

If you are under 16 please do not provide us with any personal information unless you have the permission of your parent or guardian to do so.

Telephone calls to us may be recorded and/or monitored for training purposes.

You may contact us in relation to this privacy policy by writing to us at Rolls-Royce Motor Cars Limited, The Drive, Westhampnett, Chichester. PO18 0SH, United Kingdom.
